Highest Degree:

Yashwant Choudhary () Featured

Senior Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Support, Application Support, Data Structures, Algorithms, Hibernate, MySQL, Maven, Java



Current Designation: Senior Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: QuEST Global Engineering Services Private Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Limited

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Engineer, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project

Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Support, Application

Support, Data Structures, Algorithms, Hibernate, MySQL, Maven, Java

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Total 3 years of IT experience, specializes in the development of web based applications using JAVA technologies.

Good knowledge of Spring REST web service and Micro services architecture.

Sound knowledge of Data structures & Algorithms

Total 6 years of combined experience in IT and Mechanical industry with great team management and leadership skills.

Looking for a full-time Java Backend Developer position at a Mid-Entry level in IT Industry where I can utilise my knowledge of Java, Spring and Data Structures & Algorithms for building Web Applications and able to learn new tech stack with end to end ownership

Work Experience

QuEST Global Engineering Services Private Limited as Senior Engineer

Nov 2014 to Till Date

Environment: Java, Spring, REST, Hibernate, Netflix- Eureka, Zuul, Micro services

Responsibility: Design and development of backend modules with Micro service architecture and database schema. Requirements gathering and working closely with PMs.

Description: Ops Dashboard portal provides functionality to perform worksheet and applications creation. It has functionalities of capturing scientific information uploads which are stored in S3 server and processed

by third parties. Results of the third part can be downloaded from dashboards.

Environment: Java, Spring, Velocity, Spring Scheduler

Responsibility: Enhancement development in existing projects based on business requirements.

Description: Enhancements in analytics reports generation, Sending scheduled reports.

Responsibility: Experience on Rolls-Royce Civil and Business Jets.

Description: Overhaul shops, airlines or vendors may request additional coverage within an operational timescale for any deviations or non-conformance that are not covered by formal Technical Publications.

Analytics Backend Application Quest Global Role: Software Engineer Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

Technical Variance (TV) [Non-Conformance Engineering]

72 17202 1

Quest Global

Role: Life Cycle Engineer Mar 2015 - Feb 2018

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Mechanical) from Vellore Institute of Technology (VIT) in 2014

PG: in 0

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Spring Framework, REST, Eureka, Zuul,	
Hibernate, Tomcat, MySQL, Java	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time